Shanu Kumrawat

Java Backend Developer



- Dewas, Madhya Pradesh
- kumrawat.shanu@gmail.com
- +91 8602987958 in Shanu-LinkedIn

Professional Summary

A self-motivated, hard-working and ambitious Java Backend Developer with proficiency in Java. Problem-solving mindset and the ability to perform well in collaboration. 1000+ hours of coding and hands-on experience in developing applications. Looking forward to working as an accountable and competent employee in an exciting tech company

Education

Full Stack Web Developer,

Masai School (Full-Time) 02/2022 – 11/2022

Bachelor of Engineering,

IES IPS Academy, Indore 06/2014 - 06/2018

Technical Skills

Java | SpringBoot | Spring | Maven | MySQL | Hibernate | HTML | JavaScript | CSS | Github

Soft Skills

Remote Collaboration | Team Work | Positivity | Self- Discipline | Flexibility

Interests

Travelling | Singing | Playing Musical Instrument

Projects

1) Online Plant Nursery Application 🛮

~ GitHub-link 🛮

This is Backend Application to Perform CRUD Operation and Made RestFul APIs Service for Nursery Plant Application. This is collaborative project, team of 5 member.

Features:

- Admin can Manage or can do CRUD Operation On Plants, Seeds, Planters and Customers.
- Customer can signup, login and logout see Planters, Plants and Seeds Module use Restful API.
- Customer can orders with multiple Plants, Planters and Seeds.

Tech Stack:

Java | SpringBoot | SpringData JPA | MySql | Hibernate | Lombok.

Areas of responsibility:

- Built Planter Module
- Built Plant Module

2) YOOX Website Clone 🗷

~GitHub-Link 🛮

Yoox is the world's leading online store for fashion, design and art that lasts a lifetime and beyond.

Features:

- Built Sign In Sign Up page.
- · Product filtration & details page.
- Built add to cart & apply discount.
- Built payment & Deliver address.

Tech Stack

HTML | CSS | JavaScript

Areas of responsibility

Built Product Page & Product Details Page & filtration option.

Work Experience

Senior Engineer (Project-Department),

Mayur Uniquoters Limited , Jaipur 11/2019 – 09/2020

 Prepared daily MIS of Project schedule, erection and commissioning according to site activities

GET (Graduate Engineer Trainee),

Mayur Uniquoters Limited , Jaipur 10/2018 – 10/2019

• Learn Company Software like SAP.